钱德！钱德
Chandler! Chandler!
钱德，我从窗户看见了
I saw what you were doing in the window!
我看见你在对我妹做什么了 你给我出来
I saw what you're doing to my sister! Get out here!
听着，我们玩得很开心
Listen,we had a good run.
总共4个月？5个月？
What was it? Four,five months?
比很多人一辈子加起来都久 再见，保重，再见了
That's more than most people have in a lifetime. Goodbye.
你干什么？ 我要逃跑
-What are you doing? -I am going on the lam.
过来，我应付得了罗斯
Come on,Chandler. I can handle Ross.
等一下
Hold on!
嗨 罗斯，你好吗哥哥？
Hey,Ross. What's up,bro?
你干了什么好事？ 发生什么事了？
What the hell are you doing?What's going on?
我想… 罗斯发现我和莫妮卡的事了
I think Ross knows about me and Monica.
他人就在那里
Dude,he's right there.
我以为你是我最好的朋友 这是我妹妹
I thought you were my best friend! This is my sister!
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹 我真不敢相信
My best friend and my sister! I cannot believe this!
我们不是玩玩而已，我爱她 我爱上她了
We're not just messing around. I love her.I'm in love with her.
抱歉让你这样发现
I'm so sorry that you had to find out this way.
对不起，但是真的，我也爱他
I'm sorry,but it's true. I love him too.
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹
My best friend and my sister!
我真不敢相信
I cannot believe this!
你们也想抱抱吧？大消息喔
You guys want to probably get some hugs in too. Big news!
不用了，我们知道一阵子了
We've actually known for a while.
什么？你们知道？
What? You guys knew?
你们都知道，却没告诉我？
You all knew and you didn't tell me?
我们很担心你 不知道你会有什么反应
We were worried about you. We didn't know how you were going to react.
你们担心我？ 不知道我会有什么反应？
You were worried about me?You didn't know how I'd react?
好吧，我们要不要清个场 让这对爱情鸟继续办事？
Okay. All right.Let's clear out of here and let these lovebirds get back to business.
我只是说说，上你妹的是他
I'm just talking here. He's the one doing your sister.
本集播出：“打乔伊的女孩”
The One With the Girl Who Hits Joey
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布蘭
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
“中央咖啡馆”
你们猜我想到什么 要是你们生了小孩…
You know what I just realized?If you guys have kids
我们生小孩？ 我要当教父
We're having kids?I call godfather!
你不能当教父
You can't just call godfather.
你不觉得应该由她哥哥当吗？
Shouldn't her brother be godfather?
当然，你想要的话就应该先喊
Sure. If you cared enough to call it first.
你们想得太远了 是呀，就像登月那么遥远
-You're a few steps ahead of us. -Big zero gravity moon steps.
我刚想到一样最棒的结婚礼物
I just thought of the greatest wedding gift.
我跟你送一样的，我没什么主意
I'll go in on that with you. I couldn't decide.
凯蒂
Hey,Katie.
各位，这是凯蒂
This is Katie.
可以走了吗？
You ready to go?
可以，我先上个厕所 往后走
I'll run to the bathroom.Oh sure，right back there
我们午餐要吃什么？ 我想吃中国菜
Where's for lunch?I was thinking Chinese food.
我最爱吃中国菜了
I love Chinese!
你怎么知道我爱吃中国菜？
How did you know I love Chinese?
她真可爱，可以塞进口袋里
She is so cute.You could fit her in your pocket.
可以塞进口袋的小口袋里
She could fit in that little pocket inside the pocket.
我不知道，我很喜欢她
I don't know. I like her a lot,
她人很好，但是… 但是怎样？
and she's really nice,but....But what?
她老爱打我
She keeps punching me.
用她刚才那种可爱的方式？
In the cute,little sweet way she just did?
力道比表面上大多了，好吗？ 她把我打痛了
It's a lot harder than it looks.She's hurting me.
我知道了，你需要保镖
I know what you need. You need a bodyguard.
罗斯，班下课之后有事吗？
What is Ben doing after preschool?
别这样，乔伊有烦恼
Joey is having a problem.
他被一个小女孩揍了
A little girl is beating him up.
乔伊，过来 我知道你一定非常难受…
Joey,come here.Honey,I know. This must be really difficult for you,and
抱歉，我握痛你了吗？
I'm sorry,am I hurting you?
我带了乔迁之礼来
I brought you some housewarming gifts.
盐，让你的生活有味
Salt,so your life always has flavor.
面包，让你永不饥饿
Bread,so you never go hungry.
浴室用香精蜡烛，不用我说，你知道的
And a scented candle for the bathroom.Because,well,you know.
谢谢，谢谢…再次感谢
Thanks. Thanks. And thanks,I guess.
欢迎你搬进来 我是史提夫沙拉，管委会主席
Welcome. I'm Steve Cera,president of the tenants' committee.
你好，我是罗斯盖勒 这是我朋友菲比
Ross Geller. And this is my friend Phoebe.
菲比你好 主席先生
Hi Phoebe. Mr. President.
我来跟你谈霍华的事
I came to talk to you about Howard.
霍华？ 他是这里的杂工，下星期退休
He is the handyman who's retiring next week.
这里的住户决定每人交1百元 感谢他多年来的辛劳
Everyone who lives here is kicking in $100 as a kind of a thank you.
真有人情味 是啊，所以你想开支票还是…
That's nice.Want to give me a check?
你不必现在给我 你可以塞进我家门口
Not now. You can slip it under my door.
不是那样的，我才刚搬来
No,it's not that.I just moved in.
他在这里工作了25年
Well,the guy's worked here for 25 years.
但我才搬进来25分钟
Yes,but I've lived here for 25 minutes.
好，我懂了
Okay,I get it.
等等，我很抱歉 但我甚至没见过霍华
Wait! Look,I'm sorry,it's just I've never even met Howard.
我不认识霍华 霍华是杂务工人
I mean,I don't know Howard.Howard's the handyman.
但对我来说他只是个普通人
Yes,but to me,he's just "man."
好，随便，欢迎你搬进来
Okay. Fine. Whatever.Welcome to the building.
你相信吗太不可思议了
Can you believe that guy?
是啊，我很喜欢他的眼镜
I really like his glasses.
史提夫主席逢人就说我吝啬 现在整栋楼的人都讨厌我
So then President Steve told everyone I was a cheapskate...and now the whole building hates me.
有小孩朝我的膝盖吐口水
A little kid spit on my knee.
还叫我用一百美元去擦
And told me to wipe it off with my $100 bill.
你是该擦一下
You really should wipe it off with something.
你们知道吗  我要办一场派对 邀请整栋楼的人
You know what?I'll throw a party. For everyone in the building.
我要请他们坐下，告诉他们 我不是坏人，不是吝啬
And I'll sit them all down and explain that I am not a bad guy.
我只是个坚持理念 有原则的人
I am not a cheap guy. I'm just a guy...who stands up for what he believes in.A man with principles.
听起来不错
Sounds like a fun party.
罗斯，如果你希望邻居喜欢你 为什么不付钱算了？
If you want them to like you,why don't you just pay the $100?
办一场派对更花钱
The party will cost you more.
那不重要，这是原则问题 重点是我的原则
That doesn't matter!It's my principles! We're talking about my principles!
好，我以为重点是讨邻居喜欢
I thought it was about your neighbors liking you.
等他们参加过我的派对 就会喜欢我了
They'll like me once they come to my awesome party.
我得走了，我要去买铭牌
I gotta get some nametags.
那个疯狂的派对动物将会成为你的大舅子
And that crazy party animal will be your brother-in-law.
真幽默，但别对着莫妮卡讲 别让她有那些念头
Very funny. But don't say that to Monica.Don't put any ideas in her head.
钱德，你应该知道 她可能本来就有那种念头了
You do realize that those ideas are probably already in Monica's head?
为什么？
Why?
因为她爱你，你也爱她
Well,because she loves you and because you love her.
那又怎样呢？
Yeah,so? What's that supposed to mean?
你不要被吓到 我只是在讲你知道的事
Don't freak out! I'm telling you something you already know.
她因理查不要小孩而跟他分手
She left Richard because he didn't want to have babies.
她是个女人，快30了 而且她是莫妮卡
And she is a woman. And she's almost 30. And,you know,it's Monica.
我不是那样看的 我看到两个莫妮卡
I don't see it that way. I see two Monicas.
朋友的莫妮卡住在对面 想生一大堆小孩
My friend who lives across the hall and wants a lot of babies.
另一个新的莫妮卡刚跟我交往
And the new Monica who I started to date.
谁晓得她想要什么？
Now,who is to say what she wants?
我说得没错
I'm right.
我说得没错吧？
Am I right?
当然 而且我和理查的情况完全不同
Oh,absolutely.I'm completely different from Richard.
理查是眼科医生 我连眼镜都没戴
He's an eye doctor,and I don't wear glasses.
你说得对，你说得一点也没错 情况确实完全不同
You're right.You're absolutely right. That makes everything different.
一点也没有不同对吧？ 除非不同等于一样
It's not different,is it?Not unless different means "the same."
你跟那个服务生好逗喔 你真是个疯子
You were so funny with that waiter. You're such a nut!
扮吸血鬼本来就好笑
You know,bread-stick fangs are always funny.
是你让它变好笑的，是你好笑
No,you make them funny. You're the funny one!
凯蒂，我们得沟通一下
Look,Katie. Listen,we need to talk,okay?
我喜欢你，我真的很喜欢你
Look,I like you. I really do. I like you a lot.
但当你开玩笑打我
But sometimes when you playfully punch me like that...
感觉就像被一根很小 但很结实的球棒打到
...it feels like I'm being hit with a very tiny but a very real bat!
我哪能把你打痛 你在取笑我的身材吗？
Like I could hurt you.Are you making fun of my size?
不要取笑我的身材
Don't make fun of me because of my size!
这种感觉好吗
Isn't this great?
真想永远这样
Couldn't you just stay like this forever?
钱德？你想不想永远这样？
Couldn't you just stay here forever?
这样，那样，哪样都可以
Yeah,here,somewhere else. You know,wherever.
你还好吗？ 我很好，很随性
Are you okay?I'm cool.Casual.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
只是随便混混玩玩 跟你随性的交往
Just hanging out. Having fun with the girl that I'm seeing casually.
我就知道，我就知道你会这样
Man,I knew it! I knew you'd do this.
怎样？ 被大家开玩笑结婚的事吓到
What?Get all freaked out because everybody was joking about marriage!
你的确想要那些事吧？ 你知道我想要什么？
Well,you do want all that stuff,right?You know what I want?
没错，你想要小孩 你对孩子痴狂
Yes! You want babies! You have baby fever!
我才没有对孩子痴狂
I do not have baby fever!
拜托，你超迷恋小孩和婚姻
You're obsessed with babies and marriage...
和一切跟小孩和婚姻有关的事
...and everything that's related to babies and marriage.
我有个提议 让这个压力锅减压一下吧
Why don't we turn the heat down on this pressure cooker!
你疯了吗？这不是我的问题 是你不敢做出承诺
Have you lost your mind?This isn't about me. This is about you and your weird commitment crap!
少来，我了解你 我知道你脑袋里在想什么
I know you. I know the thoughts that you have in your head.
你并非什么都知道
You don't know everything.
你知道我今晚要跟瑞秋出去而不是跟你吗
Did you know I'm going out with Rachel tonight instead of you?
你知道最幼稚的是你吗？
And that the only baby here is you?
你知道我现在都不想看到你吗？
Did you know I can't even look at you now?
那我倒是不知道
I did not know that.
不会有事吧？她不会离开我吧 这是可以解决的
It'll be okay,right? She won't leave me. This is fixable.
当然 绝对的
-Yeah,sure. -Absolutely.
我可以解决 不可能
By me? Oh No No
除非你有大动作 要非常大
Unless you make some big gesture.Big,though.
老婆来了
The missus!
甘瑟，我要一杯咖啡
Gunther,can I get a coffee?
外带
To go.
莫妮卡 我还不想跟你说话
I still don't want to talk to you.
告诉我怎样弥补
Tell me how to make things right.
什么？ 我们都这样，我做错事
What？That's what we do.I mess up,
你教我怎么补救，我补救完 你又觉得我很可爱
you tell me how to fix it and I do.And then you think I'm cute again
我不想再当你的爱情指导了 这次你得自己想，好吗？
I'm really tired of being your relationship tutor.Figure this out for yourself.
如果你对真正的关系恐惧 就别陷进去了
If you're afraid of a real relationship...then don't be in one.
（欢迎）
（罗斯）
（盖勒博士）
霍华、霍华…
Howard! Howard! Howard!
菲比？菲比
Phoebe？Phoebe
罗斯
Hi,Ross!
你在干什么？
What are you doing here?
我以为这是你的派对 结果是替霍华办的派对
I thought this was your party,and it's a party for Howard.
他真是个小可爱
He's the sweetest little man.
菲比再见，谢谢你出钱 不客气
See you,Phoebe. And thanks for chipping in.Oh,sure.
你出了钱？ 对，1百块钱
You chipped in?Yeah,$100
你居然给他们钱
I can't believe you gave him money.
你不是也同意他们要我出钱 是很不合理的？
I thought you agreed it was unreasonable that they asked me for that money.
对，但他们没有要我出
But they didn't ask me.
当性感大方的陌生人最好玩了
I'm just the exotic,generous stranger. That's always fun to be.
但你让我很难看
But you're making me look bad.
谁说的，我是在帮你加分
No,I'm not! If anything,I'm making you look better.
他们会看见你在跟我说话 我又很红
They'll see you talking to me. I'm a hit.
菲比
Hey,Phoebe!
罗斯，你们或许可以交换住处 菲比跟我们比较投缘
Hey,Ross.Maybe you two could switch apartments.Because Phoebe is more our kind of people.
你考虑一下
Think about it.
好吧 是我不好
Okay,my bad.
哇，你看起来好壮
You look big.
谢谢，我最近有在练
Thanks,I've been working out.
看得出来我穿六件毛衣吗？
Listen,is it obvious I'm wearing six sweaters?
看得出来，但看不出来为什么
Ya But it's not obvious why.
我要跟凯蒂分手 所以得多加几层护垫
I'm breaking up with Katie,so I put on some extra padding.
她平常高兴就会打我
If she hits me when she is happy,...
现在我要收回乔伊之爱 她岂不是打得更用力？
can you imagine how hard she'll hit...when I take away the Joey love?
我都忘记你的乔伊之爱了
Oh,right. I forgot that you call it that.
好可爱的外套
Hey,cute jacket.
谢谢，你真好   哦
Thanks.That's so sweet! -Ouch!
是乔伊要你叫的吗？ 你们真是够了
Did Joey tell you to say that? You guys are too much!
你知道吗？说真的 我觉得你才够了
You know what? I gotta tell you...I think you're the one that is too much.
乔伊的朋友真棒
Joey has the nicest friends.
女朋友更棒
And the nicest girlfriend.
你真好
You're so sweet!
你才好
乔伊，她踢我
Joey She just kicked me.
你不替我做点什么吗？
Aren't you going to do something?
你最好替我出头 否则我现在就走人
Do something or I'll walk out that door right now.
你要不要？
Are you going to?
不要
Nah
菲比
Phoebe
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm saying
菲比？菲比
Phoebe？Phoebe？
这真是人间地狱 我走了好不好？
This is a disaster. Can't I please just go?
不行，我正在帮你说好话
I'm talking you up to people.
再等一下下 放轻松，拿东西吃，好吗？
Give it some time,relax. Get something to eat.
你跟他们说了什么？
What did you tell them about me?
我说了你和艾蜜莉的事 好争取同情心
I told them about you and Emily. Trying to get some sympathy.
但讲一讲你成了坏人
But you came off as the bad guy.
什么？ 我想我说的方式不对
What？I told it wrong.
我们应该先聊聊 我不太知道前因后果
We should talk about that because I don't understand what happened there.
这个蛋糕真好吃
This cake is really good!
看吧？情况已经在好转了
Things are looking up.
天哪，有人切了霍华的蛋糕
Oh,my God! Someone cut Howard's cake!
谁会做这种事？
Who would do a thing like that?
3B的住户
3B
你白吃白喝，扫了大家的兴 是不是该回家了？
You got your free food. You ruined everyone's fun.Isn't it time you went home?
没错，快滚
Yeah get out Now
回3B去，3B
Go back to 3B,3B.
大家安静一下，我有话要说
Everyone,calm down! I have something that I'd like to say.
这里有谁喜欢罗斯？
Who here likes Ross?
你们当然不喜欢他
Of course you don't like him.
他不交钱 我问有谁喜欢他，他自己举手
He didn't give you any money.He raised his own hand when I asked,"Who likes Ross?"
他还贴两个铭牌
And he's wearing two nametags.
老实说，刚开始我也不喜欢他
I'll be honest. When I first met Ross,I didn't like him at all.
但了解他之后 我就发现他很贴心很大方
Once I got to know him,I saw that he is really sweet...and caring and very generous.
请不要还不了解他就论断他
All I'm saying is,don't judge Ross before you get to know him.
我现在很喜欢你们 但是刚见面时
You know,I like all of you guys now. But when I first met you,you know?
寇特，粗鲁的酒鬼
Kurt? I thought,abrasive drunk.
萝拉，笨得令人傻眼
Lola?Mind-numbingly stupid.
还有你们 淘金女，老牛吃嫩草的变态
You guys. Gold digger,cradle-robbing perv.
你们懂我的意思吧
So I think you all know what I mean.
我没想到他们会扔东西
Obviously,I didn't think they would throw things.
我想说我一直羞辱他们 你就会跳出来帮他们
I thought if I kept insulting them you'd defend them.
你就可以变成英雄 对喔
Then you'd look like the hero.Oh wow yeah
看啊 我没理解
See,I did not get that.
莫妮卡呢？我有急事找她 她在吗？
Where's Monica? I need to talk to her,it's urgent.
我就是莫妮卡
I'm Monica.
我有急事要找你 好
I need to talk to you. It's urgent.
我想了很多我们的事… 你和我的事
I've been thinking...about us. A lot of "us" thinking.
我猜只有一个办法
I guess there's only one way to do this.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
莫妮卡… 拜托不要
Monica…Don't do it.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
什么馊主意啊
What a bad idea.
我不敢看
I can't not look at it.
钱德，你为什么要这样？ 我不知道
Why are you doing this?I don't know.
但是我知道我不怕
But I know I'm not afraid to do this.
钱德 因为我很抱歉？
I'm doing this because I'm sorry?
你真的觉得结婚的最好理由 是因为你很抱歉？
Do you think the best reason to get married is because you're sorry?
不，最好的理由是未婚先孕
The best reason is pregnancy.
“抱歉”大约排第四 在“准备好了”和“真的想结婚”之后
Sorry is fourth,behind being ready and actually wanting to get married.
你愿意做我的妻子吗？
Will you be my wife?
钱德，你先静下来 想想这件事有多荒谬
I want you to take a minute and think about how ridiculous this sounds.
我的确有点希望他们都不在
I'm kind of wishing everyone wasn't here now.
这些事都不是我引出来的 我从来没说现在就想结婚生子
None of that came from me.I never said I wanted to have babies and get married!
但我真的很乱 后来又跟他们谈过
I was really confused. Then I talked to these guys.
谁？离婚两次的人和乔伊？
Who? Two divorces and Joey?
她说得对
She's right,you know?
但这仍是种奚落
Yeah,but still,cheap shot!
你知道吗？ 我不是说了要你自己想该怎么做的吗？
You know when I said that I want you...to deal with relationship stuff all on your own?
你还做不到这一点 我也这么认为
You're not ready.I didn't think I was!
天哪，要是我答应了呢？
Oh,my God.What would you have done if I had said yes?
那我会很开心 能跟心爱的人共度下半生
I would've been happy because...I would spend the rest of my life with the woman I love.
又或者你会在那扇门上 看到钱德形状的洞
Or you would have seen a Chandler-shaped hole in that door.
罗斯，请把刀子给我 我才不要
Will you pass that knife?No,I will not.
你不必这么凶吧
You don't have to be mean about it.
你说得对，对不起 嫁给我好吗？
You're right. I'm sorry. Will you marry me?
我正想向你求婚 因为我上星期忘了跟你打招呼
I was going to ask you to marry me because I didn't say hello to you.
不，菲比，那种情况应该只需要同居 但我也不确定，钱德？
Oh no wait Pheebs, I think for something like that you just ask them to move in with you. But I'm not sure, Chandler?
好，我还要被笑多久？
How long is this going to go on?
那得看你做的事有多傻 所以…会很久
I think the length of teasing...is directly related to how insane you were. So a long time.
真好玩 记得“我们分手了”风波吗？
This is fun!Remember that "we were on a break" thing?
我很抱歉，嫁给我好吗？
I'm sorry. Will you marry me?
一点也不好笑
That's not funny.